<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome to the SPiN-LAB on My New Hugo Site</title><link>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome to the SPiN-LAB on My New Hugo Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fully funded EPSRC-DTP</title><link>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/news/news-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/news/news-1/</guid><description>We are recruting!
Exploring how eye movements and pupil response during learning relate to neurotransmission: A combined neuroimaging and eye tracking study
About the Project Glutamate and GABA are two important neurotransmitters in the brain. Glutamate is the main excitatory neurotransmitter, while GABA is the main inhibitory neurotransmitter. Glutamate and GABA work together to maintain a balance between excitation and inhibition in the brain, which is essential for normal cognitive function.</description></item><item><title>New Paper</title><link>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/news/news-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/news/news-2/</guid><description>Check out our latest paper:
A Targeted, Low-Throughput Compound Screen in a Drosophila Model of Neurofibromatosis Type 1 Identifies Simvastatin and BMS-204352 as Potential Therapies for Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) Dyson A, Ryan M, Garg S, Evans DG, Baines RA. eNeuro, DOI: 10.1523/ENEURO.0461-22.2023</description></item><item><title>MRI Preparation</title><link>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/mri-preparation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/mri-preparation/</guid><description>Enim consequat sunt esse fugiat fugiat fugiat sint adipisicing ex ullamco dolor cupidatat quis. Cillum tempor labore laboris cillum aliquip incididunt velit elit deserunt. Aute nulla ex laboris proident et reprehenderit officia quis elit nisi Lorem. Consectetur sit magna duis ullamco aliquip incididunt nostrud elit est consequat sunt sit.</description></item><item><title>Caroline Lea-Carnall</title><link>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/people/caroline/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/people/caroline/</guid><description>Labore duis aute ex id voluptate irure duis esse. Consequat voluptate commodo reprehenderit mollit officia mollit nulla proident esse proident voluptate ad magna. Nisi magna do aliquip cupidatat consectetur fugiat in magna. Exercitation mollit aliqua labore est nisi dolore. Pariatur reprehenderit in aute exercitation Lorem esse incididunt exercitation fugiat sunt proident quis. Eu ipsum quis elit voluptate labore voluptate voluptate consequat ea exercitation reprehenderit sit. Veniam amet Lorem aute quis.</description></item><item><title>Shruti Garg</title><link>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/people/shruti/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/people/shruti/</guid><description>I did my general medical training at Grant Medical College, Mumbai India beofre training in general psychiatry at Oxford &amp;amp; Leeds. I moved to Manchester in 2008 to specialise in Child &amp;amp; Adolescent Psychiatry. I was awarded a research training fellowship by NIHR Bioedical Research centre in 2011-12 to study the behavioural phenotype of Neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1). My PhD thesis described for the first time, a high prevalence of Autism Spectrum Disorders (ASD) in NF1.</description></item><item><title>Varun Chandran</title><link>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/people/varun/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/people/varun/</guid><description>Varun Arunachalam Chandran, PhD
Postdoctoral Research Associate- Faculty of biology, medicine and health, University of Manchester
Email: varun.chandran@manchester.ac.uk
Currently, I work as a postdoctoral research associate for a study titled ‘Neuroimaging in Rasopathies’ (funded by NIHR-BRC) at the faculty of biology, medicine and health, University of Manchester, United Kingdom. In the current research project, we examine the inhibitory/excitatory imbalance associated with GABA/glutamate, functional connectivity and myelin differences underpinning learning and working memory difficulties in children with Rasopathies specifically including Neurofibromatosis type-I and Noonan Syndrome as well as its phenotypic relationship with Autism Spectrum Conditions (ASC).</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/about/</guid><description>[We should habe a tem pic here!]
We are a research group interested in brain plasticity during neurodevelopment. We use a combination of advanced brain imaging and computational methods to understand how brain plasticity in altered in certain genetic conditions and how that affects learning.
There is a translational focus to our work where we examine the physiological mechanisms of learning and memory identified in animal models in human clinical cohorts, thereby addressing critical translational gap form animal models to humans.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/contact/</guid><description>This is an example of a custom shortcode that you can put right into your content. You will need to add a form action to the the shortcode to make it work. Check out Formspree for a simple, free form service.
Your Name Email Address An email address is required. Message</description></item><item><title>Lab Manual</title><link>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/lab-manual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/lab-manual/</guid><description>Elit veniam ex ad mollit consequat deserunt. Dolore minim aute in eu laborum fugiat cupidatat laboris. Irure occaecat quis sunt ea elit nisi ad. Consectetur esse qui quis pariatur enim laborum velit laborum qui in est non sunt. Voluptate magna quis commodo commodo sint labore nisi proident sint ad occaecat veniam.</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carolineleac.github.io/spin-lab-site/publications/</guid><description>The latest publications from the lab.
2023 Noise-modulated multistable synapses in a Wilson-Cowan-based model of plasticity Lea-Carnall CA, Tanner LI, Montemurro MA. Front Comput Neurosci, DOI: 10.3389/fncom.2023.1017075
A mean-field model of glutamate and GABA synaptic dynamics for functional MRS Lea-Carnall CA, El-Deredy W, Stagg CJ, Williams SR, Trujillo-Barreto NJ. NeuroImage, DOI: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2022.119813
A Targeted, Low-Throughput Compound Screen in a Drosophila Model of Neurofibromatosis Type 1 Identifies Simvastatin and BMS-204352 as Potential Therapies for Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) Dyson A, Ryan M, Garg S, Evans DG, Baines RA.</description></item></channel></rss>